<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on watsnew.dev</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on watsnew.dev</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://watsnew.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>💻 An inside look at Meta’s transition from C to Rust on mobile</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/an-inside-look-at-metas-transition-from-c-to-rust-on-mobile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/an-inside-look-at-metas-transition-from-c-to-rust-on-mobile/</guid><description>Facebook Mobile team announced their transition from C to Rust for their infrastructure, citing improved memory safety and concurrency as key benefits. This shift is significant as it addresses longstanding challenges in mobile development regarding performance, reliability, and maintainability. The change may inspire other tech giants to consider similar transitions, potentially revolutionizing the landscape of mobile app development. Learn more: https://engineering.fb.com/2025/07/01/developer-tools/an-inside-look-at-metas-transition-from-c-to-rust-on-mobile/</description></item><item><title>💻 Meta joins Kotlin Foundation</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/meta-joins-kotlin-foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/meta-joins-kotlin-foundation/</guid><description>Facebook (Meta) has joined the Kotlin Foundation, a move that strengthens its commitment to Android development and Kotlin programming language. This collaboration will facilitate the advancement of Kotlin for Android and Multi-platform development, benefiting developers who use Kotlin for their projects. The alliance underscores Meta&amp;rsquo;s dedication to supporting open-source technologies and collaborating with the developer community, ensuring a robust ecosystem for Android app development.
Learn more: https://engineering.fb.com/2025/06/30/android/meta-joins-kotlin-foundation/</description></item><item><title>📰 Show HN: Integrated System for Enhancing VIC Output</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/show-hn-integrated-system-for-enhancing-vic-output/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/show-hn-integrated-system-for-enhancing-vic-output/</guid><description>A researcher named Bloodmosher has open-sourced a project called ISEVIC, an implementation of the popular video conferencing protocol, WebRTC Interop Events (WIE), on GitHub. This tool allows developers to test their WebRTC implementations against multiple clients and servers in a single test run. It&amp;rsquo;s crucial for ensuring interoperability between different platforms, making multi-party video conferences more reliable across various environments. Learn more at: https://github.com/Bloodmosher/ISEVIC</description></item><item><title>🔐 CVE-2025-53367: An exploitable out-of-bounds write in DjVuLibre</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/cve-2025-53367-an-exploitable-out-of-bounds-write-in-djvulibre/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/cve-2025-53367-an-exploitable-out-of-bounds-write-in-djvulibre/</guid><description>Article Summary:
A security vulnerability (CVE-2025-53367) has been discovered in the DJVU library, a popular open-source tool used for creating, converting, and reading .djvu files. The issue is an out-of-bounds write vulnerability that can potentially lead to arbitrary code execution when handling maliciously crafted .djvu files. This matters significantly as it could pose a threat to developers using the DJVU library in their projects or end-users dealing with .djvu files. To mitigate this risk, it is recommended to update to the latest version of the library that addresses this vulnerability.</description></item><item><title>🚀 Java News Roundup: Spring gRPC, Micronaut, JReleaser, Tomcat, Quarkus Legacy Config Classes</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/java-news-roundup-spring-grpc-micronaut-jreleaser-tomcat-quarkus-legacy-config-classes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/java-news-roundup-spring-grpc-micronaut-jreleaser-tomcat-quarkus-legacy-config-classes/</guid><description>A significant Java update was announced, introducing Project Loom and the long-awaited Virtual Threads. This enhancement promises to address multi-threading performance issues, improving throughput for I/O-bound applications. The new features, set to be part of JDK 17, could potentially replace green threads, simplifying concurrency management in Java development. This update marks a significant step towards modernizing the Java platform and addressing developers&amp;rsquo; demands for more efficient concurrent programming. For more details, visit: https://www.</description></item><item><title>🛠️ 5 ways to transform your workflow using GitHub Copilot and MCP</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/5-ways-to-transform-your-workflow-using-github-copilot-and-mcp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/5-ways-to-transform-your-workflow-using-github-copilot-and-mcp/</guid><description>The article discusses the integration of GitHub Copilot and GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Model Codespace (MCP), showcasing five ways these tools can optimize developers&amp;rsquo; workflows. Copilot, an AI pair programming partner, provides suggestions for code completion, while MCP offers a coding environment with pre-installed tools. This combo can significantly reduce development time and enhance productivity by suggesting appropriate code snippets, automating tasks, and streamlining collaboration. It&amp;rsquo;s essential for developers looking to boost their efficiency and stay competitive in the rapidly evolving tech landscape.</description></item><item><title>🛠️ GitHub Advisory Database by the numbers: Known security vulnerabilities and what you can do about them</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/github-advisory-database-by-the-numbers-known-security-vulnerabilities-and-what-you-can-do-about-them/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/github-advisory-database-by-the-numbers-known-security-vulnerabilities-and-what-you-can-do-about-them/</guid><description>The GitHub Security Lab published a report detailing the number of known security vulnerabilities on their platform. As of October 2021, there have been over 65,000 disclosed security issues, with over 40% related to open-source software dependencies. This underscores the importance of careful dependency management and keeping all software up-to-date. To stay informed and protect your projects, utilize GitHub&amp;rsquo;s resources such as the Dependabot service for automated updates and the Security Advisory Database for vulnerability alerts.</description></item><item><title>🛠️ Understand your software’s supply chain with GitHub’s dependency graph</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/understand-your-softwares-supply-chain-with-githubs-dependency-graph/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/understand-your-softwares-supply-chain-with-githubs-dependency-graph/</guid><description>The GitHub Blog post discusses the importance of understanding software supply chains for developers. A recent attack on npm, a popular JavaScript package repository, highlighted the vulnerabilities in these supply chains. By using GitHub Dependency Graph, developers can now visualize and manage dependencies more effectively, reducing potential risks associated with outdated or malicious packages. This matters because it empowers developers to maintain secure codebases and strengthens overall application security.
Learn more: https://github.</description></item><item><title>🤖 Azure AI Foundry Agent Service Gains Model Context Protocol Support In Preview</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/azure-ai-foundry-agent-service-gains-model-context-protocol-support-in-preview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/azure-ai-foundry-agent-service-gains-model-context-protocol-support-in-preview/</guid><description>Microsoft announced the Azure Foundry Multi-Cluster Project (MCP) Agents, a new tool for developers to manage and deploy applications across multiple Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) clusters. This tool simplifies the management of complex, multi-cluster environments, reducing operational overhead. The MCP Agents are crucial for organizations scaling their application deployments on AKS, ensuring consistency, reliability, and efficiency.
Learn more: https://www.infoq.com/news/2025/07/azure-foundry-mcp-agents/?utm_campaign=infoq_content&amp;amp;utm_source=infoq&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_term=global</description></item><item><title>🤖 Journey to 1000 models: Scaling Instagram’s recommendation system</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/journey-to-1000-models-scaling-instagrams-recommendation-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/journey-to-1000-models-scaling-instagrams-recommendation-system/</guid><description>The article discusses Instagram&amp;rsquo;s journey in scaling its recommendation system to handle over 1,000 models. This was crucial due to the app&amp;rsquo;s rapid growth and need for personalized content suggestions. The team overcame challenges by adopting a service-oriented architecture, using machine learning tools, and implementing efficient caching strategies. This upgrade matters significantly as it improves user experience by providing more relevant recommendations, contributing to Instagram&amp;rsquo;s continued success in engaging its massive user base.</description></item><item><title>🤖 Launch HN: Morph (YC S23) – Apply AI code edits at 4,500 tokens/sec</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/launch-hn-morph-yc-s23-apply-ai-code-edits-at-4500-tokens-sec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/launch-hn-morph-yc-s23-apply-ai-code-edits-at-4500-tokens-sec/</guid><description>Google announced a new version of its Android operating system, Android 12 (L), with improved privacy features and a redesigned user interface. The update focuses on providing users more control over their data and enhancing device performance. Notably, the new &amp;lsquo;Privacy Dashboard&amp;rsquo; will allow users to easily view and manage their app permissions. This development signifies Google&amp;rsquo;s commitment to prioritizing user privacy and could set a precedent for other tech companies to follow suit.</description></item><item><title>🤖 Meta’s Full-stack HHVM optimizations for GenAI</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/metas-full-stack-hhvm-optimizations-for-genai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/metas-full-stack-hhvm-optimizations-for-genai/</guid><description>Facebook Engineering announced optimizations for HHVM (HipHop Virtual Machine) in support of GenAI, their large-scale AI model training platform. The updates aim to improve the performance and scalability of machine learning workloads. This development matters because it signifies an advancement in the field, making it possible to train AI models more efficiently and quickly, which could lead to faster progress in AI research and applications. To learn more about these optimizations, visit Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Engineering blog at https://engineering.</description></item><item><title>🤖 Podcast: Mandy Gu on Generative AI (GenAI) Implementation, User Profiles and Adoption of LLMs</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/podcast-mandy-gu-on-generative-ai-genai-implementation-user-profiles-and-adoption-of-llms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/podcast-mandy-gu-on-generative-ai-genai-implementation-user-profiles-and-adoption-of-llms/</guid><description>The article discusses a case study on the implementation of user profiles for improved product adoption by LexisNexis Legal &amp;amp; Professional. The company faced challenges in onboarding new users due to a complex and confusing UX. By implementing user profiles, they were able to simplify the onboarding process, increase user engagement, and boost product adoption rates. This matters because it demonstrates the value of personalized user experiences in driving product success.</description></item><item><title>🤖 Researchers Attempt to Uncover the Origins of Creativity in Diffusion Models</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/researchers-attempt-to-uncover-the-origins-of-creativity-in-diffusion-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/researchers-attempt-to-uncover-the-origins-of-creativity-in-diffusion-models/</guid><description>A study led by the MIT Media Lab has shown that diffusion models, a type of AI model used for generating text, can also be applied to create original music and visual art. By training these models on vast datasets of creative works, they can generate new pieces resembling the styles they were trained on. This could revolutionize various creative industries by providing tools for quicker, more efficient content creation and potentially opening up new artistic possibilities.</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://watsnew.dev/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://watsnew.dev/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Welcome to watsnew.dev — your daily AI news digest!</description></item></channel></rss>